<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>7/25/2018</updated>
  <id>http://news.kcc.edu/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Kankakee Community College</title>
  

  
    <subtitle></subtitle>
  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Register Now for Fall 2018</title>
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/register-now-for-fall-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Register Now for  Fall 2018" />
      <published>7/19/2018</published>
      <updated>7/19/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/register-now-for-fall-2018</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/register-now-for-fall-2018.html">&lt;p&gt;Kankakee Community College is offering a variety of fall enrollment options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options are listed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/schedule&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/schedule&lt;/a&gt;, and include viewing classes by subject, location, time of day, or course type—such as online or hybrid. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The college’s fall semester begins the week of Monday, Aug. 21. Early registration is encouraged for the best selection of classes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registration and advisement is available in person in Student Services at KCC, which is located on the second floor of the Workforce Development Center KCC is south of downtown Kankakee, off River Road, near U.S. 45 52, or take Interstate 57 to Exit 308 and follow the signs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registration hours are 8 a.m. - 6 p.m. Monday through Thursday and 8 a.m. - 5 p.m. Fridays. College offices will be closed July 20 and 27. Qualified returning students can register online. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New and returning students unsure of the enrollment process can contact the Office of Student Services, 815-802-8500 or visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/register&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/register&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KCC Miner South Extension Center, 1488 E. Walnut St. in Watseka, also offers registration and advisement. The extension center is open Monday through Thursday 8:30 a.m. - 9 p.m., and closed Fridays. Advisement in Watseka is available Tuesdays and Thursdays, and by appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/sidewalk-dsc-0293.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-interesting-kcc-facts&quot;&gt;8 interesting KCC facts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rated #1 in Illinois by Zippia.com for helping students land a job after graduation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top 10% of community colleges in the nation for students who complete a career program and find employment in a related field.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top 15% of community colleges in the nation for first-time, full-time students who transfer within 2 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The latest pass rates for all health career licensure exams are above the national average, with most at 100%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ranked #2 in North America among associate degree colleges for sustainability practices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average age of Dec. 2017 &amp;amp; May 2018 Associate degree graduates is 26.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practical Nursing program ranked No. 2 in Illinois.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More high school graduates in this area enroll at KCC than any other college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources: KCC Office of Institutional Research, National Community College Benchmark Project (comparison to other participating community colleges); &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aashe.org/news/2017-sustainable-campus-index-released/&quot;&gt;Association for the Advancement of Sustainability in Higher Education&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zippia.com&quot;&gt;zippia.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.practicalnursing.org&quot;&gt;www.practicalnursing.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Kankakee Community College is offering a variety of fall enrollment options.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/art-class-dsc-4391.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Perfect streak continues for X-ray program</title>
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/perfect-streak-continues-for-x-ray-program.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Perfect streak continues for X-ray program" />
      <published>7/19/2018</published>
      <updated>7/19/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/perfect-streak-continues-for-x-ray-program</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/perfect-streak-continues-for-x-ray-program.html">&lt;p&gt;For the 11th consecutive year, Kankakee Community College graduates have a 100 percent pass rate on the American Registry of Radiologic Technologists National Certification Examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 14 graduates in the class of 2018 took the test between May and July. National comparison information will be available in January. Since 2013, the national pass rates have ranged from 87.2 percent to 93.3 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who pass the test carry the credentials of Registered Radiologic Technologist.&lt;br /&gt;Candidates were required to earn a minimum mean scaled score of 75 to pass, and KCC’s graduates had scores ranging from 75 to 93, said Darla Jepson, director of KCC’s Radiography Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KCC offers a two-year associate degree in radiography, which trains students for careers in radiologic technology. In addition to being eligible for the AART certification exam, graduates are also automatically eligible for a license with the Illinois Emergency Management Agency, Division of Nuclear Safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about KCC’s Radiography Program, contact Jepson at djepson@kcc.edu or 815-802-8832.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">KCC grads earn 100% pass rate on the ARRT National Certification Exam.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/radiography-dsc-2162.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">KCC passes VA audit</title>
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/kcc-passes-va-audit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KCC passes VA audit" />
      <published>7/19/2018</published>
      <updated>7/19/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/kcc-passes-va-audit</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/19/kcc-passes-va-audit.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;KCC’s veteran’s services team has passed a Veteran’s Affairs audit with flying colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Federal VA audit resulted in no issues, with no findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The college expects to receive an official letter to confirm the results within the next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a team effort, as many of us work with the veterans; completing vouchers, registering them, approving degree audits, certifying, payments, etc.,” said Deanna Liacone, director of financial aid. Liacone made special mention of contributions made by Kendra Souligne, coordinator in the Financial Aid Office; Michele Buikema, administrative assistant for the Information/Finance Office; and Vanessa Lopez, specialist II in the Financial Aid Office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KCC offers a number of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/future/paying/fedstateaid/veteran-services/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;services for veterans&lt;/a&gt;, including a Veterans Resource Center.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">KCC’s veteran’s services team has passed a Veteran’s Affairs audit with flying colors.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/veterans-dsc-0536-1.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Fall 2018 classes at SEC</title>
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/07/fall-2018-classes-at-sec.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fall 2018 classes at SEC" />
      <published>7/7/2018</published>
      <updated>7/7/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/07/fall-2018-classes-at-sec</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/07/07/fall-2018-classes-at-sec.html">&lt;p&gt;College credit classes include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Business (BSNS 1553) on Wednesdays from 6-8:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PowerPoint (COSC 1341) on Mondays from 1-2:40 p.m. beginning Oct. 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Word (COSC 1352) on Mondays and Wednesdays from 10-11:40 a.m. beginning Oct. 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Information Processing (COSC 1513) on Tuesdays and Thursdays from 5-6:40 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English I (ENGL 1613) on Thursdays from 6-8:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phlebotomy Techniques (HLTH 1404) on Mondays and Wednesdays, 9:30 -11:40 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentals of Mathematics (MATH 0974) on Tuesdays and Thursdays from 5-6:40 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Algebra (MATH 1414) on Tuesdays and Thursdays from 7-8:40 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adult Education classes include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High School Equivalency Preparation on Mondays and Wednesdays from 9 a.m. - 12:30 p.m. and 5:30-9 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English as a Second Language (ESL) on Mondays and Tuesdays from 6-9 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An orientation is required to enroll in high school equivalency and ESL classes. Please phone 815-802-8780 to sign up for an orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Miner South Extension Center is at 1488 E Walnut St. in Watseka. Registration and advising hours at the SEC are Tuesdays, 4-7 p.m. and Thursdays, 8:30 a.m. - 5 p.m. Other hours available by appointment. For more information and to schedule an appointment with an advisor, call 815-802-8780.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">​South Extension Center has seats available in a variety of courses for fall.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/kcc_default_post-placeholder.png" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Lifelong Learning Institute</title>
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/21/lifelong-learning-institute.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lifelong Learning Institute" />
      <published>6/21/2018</published>
      <updated>6/21/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/21/lifelong-learning-institute</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/21/lifelong-learning-institute.html">&lt;p&gt;For more information or to find out the latest course offerings, please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/lli&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.kcc.edu/lli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Stimulating intellectual and cultural pursuits, for active people 50 and up.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/kcc_default_post-placeholder.png" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Coaching Book Author Has Deep KCC Roots</title>
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/12/coaching-book-author-has-deep-kcc-roots.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching Book Author Has Deep KCC Roots" />
      <published>6/12/2018</published>
      <updated>6/12/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/12/coaching-book-author-has-deep-kcc-roots</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/12/coaching-book-author-has-deep-kcc-roots.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/DHolstein.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt;Dr. David Holstein. a long-time junior college coach and administrator has written C3: Christ Centered Coaching, Utilizing Faith to Impact Athletes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A KCC alumnus, Holstein spent three decades coaching basketball at KCC, 17 as an assistant and 13 as head coach. He also was KCC’s athletic director for 15 years. After retiring from KCC in 2008, Holstein served as athletic administrator at Palm Beach State College in Florida for eight years. Holstein-Book-Cover&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../uploads/Holstein-Book-Cover150x150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of Dr. David Holstein's book C3: Christ Centered Coaching&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid float-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As it is in the athletic world where our student athletes have been bestowed with physical skills, we as believers have been provided with spiritual skills,” Holstein said. “In both worlds I feel we have an obligation to develop those skills because they are gifts from the Lord Jesus Christ. Our journey as coaches of faith and our mandate is to develop our witness with the power of the platform. My prayer is that through the witness of C3, coaches of faith will continue to grow and mature in the knowledge of the Lord and transcend that in whatever way they choose is right for them. In addition, I would hope because of the leadership dialogue in C3 that non-believers picking C3 up will consider a Christian way of life as a good way to enhance their world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C3 will be available online at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/C3-Centered-Coaching-Utilizing-Athletes/dp/1632694670&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/c3-dr-db-holstein/1128310908?&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Barnes and Noble&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://deepriverbooks.com/books/c3-christ-centered-coaching/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Deep River Books&lt;/a&gt; beginning June 14.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Dr. David Holstein. a long-time junior college coach and administrator has written . . .</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/DHolstein.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Linkedin Seminar June 27</title>
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/11/linkedin-seminar-june-27.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linkedin Seminar June 27" />
      <published>6/11/2018</published>
      <updated>6/11/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/11/linkedin-seminar-june-27</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/06/11/linkedin-seminar-june-27.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Breitbarth_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt;“Everyone is marketing something—whether it’s yourself or your business,” said the presenter, Wayne Breitbarth. “Don’t let another day pass without acquiring the knowledge you need to open doors and get dramatic results.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seminar will have two presentations, and participants can attend one or both. Registration is not required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“LinkedIn: A Student’s Fast Track to Internships and Jobs” will be from 10 a.m. - noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’re interested in quickly and easily creating a strong LinkedIn presence and growing a network that will open doors, this class is for you,” Breitbarth said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics relate to using LinkedIn to finding a job, including creating a winning profile, tapping into a database of resources, developing a network, the best keywords, and connecting with school alumni to locate opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Power Formula for LinkedIn Success” will be from 1:30-3:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This class has something for everyone,” Breitbarth said. “Whether you’re a social media novice or savvy user, you’ll come away with action steps that can produce immediate results.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics will include using your experience and relationships to meet your business and career goals, creating a compelling profile that helps the right people find you, successfully searches, engaging with LinkedIn members who can help you, and using hidden LinkedIn features to generate opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/breitbarth-3rd-edition-3D-whitebg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-right&quot; /&gt;Breitbarth is the CEO of Power Formula LLC. He has shared his expertise with more than 80,000 business professionals through private business consulting, dynamic presentations to worldwide audiences, and his critically acclaimed book The Power Formula for LinkedIn Success (now in its third edition). He has been featured in Forbes, Inc., Wired, and American Express Open Forum and seen on NBC and Fox Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breitbarth is also a certified public accountant, with degrees from the University of Wisconsin-Whitewater and Marquette University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event is sponsored by KCC’s Office of Career Services and the KCC Young Adult Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit the career preparation workshops page at www.kcc.edu/careerservices or phone Ken Crite, coordinator of KCC’s Career Services Center, at 815-802-8222.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">A free seminar to help job seekers and others harness the power of LinkedIn will be on Wednesday, June 27 at Kankakee Community College.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/Breitbarth-Headshot-July-2015.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
