<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>8/23/2018</updated>
  <id>http://news.kcc.edu/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Kankakee Community College</title>
  

  
    <subtitle></subtitle>
  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Food Sanitation and Safety course</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/23/food-sanitation-and-safety-course.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Food Sanitation and Safety course" />
      <published>8/23/2018</published>
      <updated>8/23/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/23/food-sanitation-and-safety-course</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/23/food-sanitation-and-safety-course.html">&lt;p&gt;A Food Sanitation and Safety course is being offered this fall at Kankakee Community College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course prepares individuals for the National Registry of Food Safety Professionals exam, which is approved by the state of Illinois and the Conference for Food Protection. This certification is recognized nationwide and is valid for five years. The course and exam are offered in the same day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course meets the new requirements for re-certification which went into effect on July 1, 2014. To meet the new requirements, a food service professional must complete an eight-hour Food Sanitation and Safety course and pass the re-certification exam every five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class will meet 9 a.m. - 6 p.m. Monday, Sept. 24 in Room D124 at KCC.  The course number is HLTH 520A.A23 and the $139 fee includes the book. Exam retakes are $35, and the payment is required prior to the re-take. Students can pick up a study guide prior to the first class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course does not award college credit. To register or for more information, call 815-802-8207; go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&lt;/a&gt;; or visit the Welcome Center.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Prepare for the National Registry of Food Safety Professionals exam.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/Food-tree.png" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Seminar: 1st Six Sessions of Therapy</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/seminar-1st-six-sessions-of-therapy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar: 1st Six Sessions of Therapy" />
      <published>8/22/2018</published>
      <updated>8/22/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/seminar-1st-six-sessions-of-therapy</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/seminar-1st-six-sessions-of-therapy.html">&lt;p&gt;The Continuing Education Department at Kankakee Community College is offering a seminar for social workers and counselors in September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The First Six Session of Therapy” is designed to help practitioners increase first session attendance, engage clients in the first five minutes of contact, and increase attendance in future sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presenter, Mark Sanders, said there is research which shows that clients make the most progress in the first six weeks of counseling, but most are no-shows at the second session. The seminar is designed to help turn around those statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics will include feedback informed counseling, behavioral couples counseling, motivational incentives and stage-based incentives. Sanders also will share information on how to accelerate progress through tasks and overcome resistance within the first three sessions of counseling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanders is an author and speaker on behavioral health issues. His presentations have reached thousands throughout the U.S., Europe, Canada, the Caribbean and British Islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seminar meets Friday, Sept. 14 from 8:30 a.m. - 4 p.m. at KCC in the Iroquois Room. Course no. is HLTH 438A.A13. Cost is $79, and includes handouts and 6 contact hours for nurses, nursing home administrators, social workers and counselors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course does not award college credit. To register or for more information. Call 815-802-8207; go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&lt;/a&gt; (choose KCC Connect and search by course number); or visit the Welcome Center, located on the first floor of the KCC Workforce Development Center.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Learn to get clients to increase attendance at therapy sessions.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/pexels-advise-answer-arrow-208494.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Online classes offered for personal enrichment</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/online-classes-offered-for-personal-enrichment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online classes offered for personal enrichment" />
      <published>8/22/2018</published>
      <updated>8/22/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/online-classes-offered-for-personal-enrichment</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/online-classes-offered-for-personal-enrichment.html">&lt;p&gt;The Continuing Education Department at Kankakee Community College is offering online classes for personal enrichment this fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Beginning Conversational French” includes practical, common French phrases which are useful for those visiting a French-speaking region of the world. Topics will include speaking in various situations and learning some cultural tips. Cost is $94.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Conversational Japanese” class will be guided by a native Japanese instructor. Participants will gain cultural knowledge, useful conversational phrases and vocabulary words particular to a specific area of travel. Audio aids and Japanese words written in the English alphabet will also be offered. Cost is $94.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Introduction to Interior Design” teaches how to transform plain living spaces into beautiful and functional rooms. Lessons will include designs from floor to ceiling, color theory, industry trends, floor plans and other basics. Careers in interior design will be introduced. Cost is $94.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Creating a Successful Business Plan” shares methods to turn business ideas into a solid plan for financing and long-term success. The course covers creating a business plan, which is often a difficult first step on the path to small business success. Cost is $94.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “SAT/ACT Prep Series” has two courses, one to prepare for the math section and the other to prepare for the verbal questions. It helps students maximize time on each portion of the tests. Weekly assignments encourage work with your classmates and the instructor to maximize performance on the ACT/SAT. Cost is $199.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start date options for all courses are Sept. 12, Oct. 17, Nov. 14 and Dec. 12. These courses do not award college credit. More information and registration is at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ed2go.com/kankakeecc/&quot;&gt;ed2go.com/kankakeecc&lt;/a&gt;. For more information or to make a payment, phone KCC at 815-802-8206.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Fall classes offer various learning opportunities.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/pexel-design-expression-learn-247819.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Job Search Boot Camp sessions</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/job-search-boot-camp-sessions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Job Search Boot Camp sessions" />
      <published>8/22/2018</published>
      <updated>8/22/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/job-search-boot-camp-sessions</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/job-search-boot-camp-sessions.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/group-photo-job-fair.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/coned/careerservices/Pages/jobfairs.aspx&quot;&gt;Career Services Center&lt;/a&gt; at Kankakee Community College is offering five free seminars on job search skills this fall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Job Search: What Works &amp;amp; What Doesn’t” includes how to properly complete an employment application, find and use various job searching tools, best practices for submitting resumes and proper follow up techniques. Meets 5:30-7 p.m. Wednesday, Aug. 29 at KCC in Room D122. Course number is LECT 8920.Q13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Preparing for Your Interview” teaches how to approach your next interview with increased confidence by learning tips that help an applicant land a job. Meets 5:30-7 p.m. Thursday, Sept. 19 at KCC in Room D123. Course number is LECT 9035.Q13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Working a Job Fair: How to Improve Your Odds” gives insight on how a job fair is structured and how to impress area employers. Meets 5:30-7 p.m. Thursday, Sept. 27 at KCC in Room D123. Course number is LECT 9057.Q13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Nuts and Bolts of Writing a Good Resume and Cover Letter” shares how to create a job objective that gets results and showcase employment and education background in a chronologically formatted resume. Components of a successful cover letter also will be reviewed. Meets 5:30-7 p.m. Wednesday, Oct. 17 at KCC in Room D123. Course number is LECT 9034.Q13.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Develop Your Job Search Tool Kit Using Social Media” helps participants develop a job search tool kit by using traditional and nontraditional job search methods such as social media outlets, College Central, LinkedIn and much more. Meets 5:30-7 p.m. Wednesday Nov. 14 at KCC in Room D123. Course number is LECT 8920.Q23.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructor for each session is Ken Crite, coordinator of career services for KCC. The sessions do not award college credit. To register for any of these free sessions, or for more information, call 815-802-8207; go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&lt;/a&gt; (choose KCConnect and search by course number); or visit the KCC Welcome Center on the first floor of the Workforce Development Center.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Get ready for KCC's Job Fair with these seminars.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/group-photo-job-fair.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">2018-19 Foundation Scholarship Recipients</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/2018-19-foundation-scholarship-recipients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018-19 Foundation Scholarship Recipients" />
      <published>8/22/2018</published>
      <updated>8/22/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/2018-19-foundation-scholarship-recipients</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/2018-19-foundation-scholarship-recipients.html">&lt;p&gt;Following are scholarships and the recipients for 2018-19 scholarships awarded by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/foundation&quot;&gt;KCC Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 To Finish: Zachary Bacon, Piaget Felix and Antonio Petrongelli.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 To Finish-FT (15+hrs): Luke Engelman.Al &amp;amp; Emma Lou Lemon Scholarship for Education Students:  Kylee Boudreau and Kristen Bodemer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Americo Vespucci Lodge 1722 Scholarship: Andrew Douglas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Azzarelli, Raymond and Carmella Memorial Nursing Endowed Scholarship: Emma Goudreau and MeghannHeck.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Azzarelli, Raymond and CarmellaGeneral Academic Memorial Endowed Scholarship: Austin Ziman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beulah Cromwell Scholarship: Austin Boudreau.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C. Max Hoover Scholarship: Joseph Roach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cavalier Scholarship for Academic Excellence: Andrew Boudreau, Ianeli Medina, Nickolas Pomykala, Abbey Boudreau, Michael Boyd, Noah Bramer, Jacob Duffy, Aurora Rivera and Preston VanSwol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Central Illinois Green Club Agriculture/Horticulture Scholarship: Donna Beland.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Century Scholarship: Damon Myers Karla Rodriguez-Ramirez and ErronSmith.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charles E. Hubbard Jr. Memorial Scholarship: Emmanuel Bannerman-Blankson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charlton Family Visual and Fine Arts Endowed Scholarship: Gabrielle Schultz.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chuck Smead Scholarship: Lexie McCleary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clancy-Gernon Scholarship: Hannah Salzman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Commonwealth Credit Union Scholarship:  Ben Randak.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cora S. Speicher Scholarship: ElyseGustafson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cora S. Speicher Scholarship: HollyLease, ChloeeSchuldt, HannahAskew and KaileyGash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coyote Canyon Scholarship:  LaurenBuschek.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CSL Behring, L.L.C. Endowed Scholarship: Emmanuel Bannerman-Blankson, Quinnton Becker and Haley McDaniel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultural Diversity Awareness Scholarship: Mackenzie Delby.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cynthia Steury-Lattz Memorial Scholarship: Lisa Schamber.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dennis J. Smith Legacy Endowed Scholarship: Luke Engelman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divisional Scholarships – Business: Alisha Wright; Health Careers: Kaelyn Anderson and Megan Lumbrezer; Humanities: Andrew Boudreau and Yaneli Pizano; Technology: Felicia Goodrich and RileyThomas; Math, Science, and Engineering: Connor Jumonville and Claire Tanner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do It Stevie’s Way- Proven IT- BBCHS: Ben Randak; Central: Gabriella Griffith; Grace Christian Academy: Lauren Hertz; Kankakee High School: Ianeli Medina; Manteno High School: Nickolas Pomykala; Milford High School: Hailey Osborn; Momence: Noah Bramer; St. Anne: Payton Kerness; Watseka (District 9): Emily Bunting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don James Memorial Scholarship: Andrew Boudreau.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donald L. Haley Memorial Endowed Scholarship: Jeffery Gifford.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dorothy and Walter Franklin Endowed Scholarship: Hannia Garcia and Monique Mays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dorothy W. Franklin GED Annual Scholarship: Holly Gilliam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dotty Lagesse Endowed Scholarship: Kerri Skiles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dr. Victor Hopper Endowed Scholarship: Gabriella Griffith.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dreamer Scholarship: Jesus Andrade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E. Kenneth Chipman Memorial Scholarship: Nicholas Barnes and Megan Lanie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eastern Illinois Law Enforcement Administrators Association Criminal Justice/ Law Enforcement Annual Scholarship: Elan Benge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eileen Van Voorst Memorial Endowed Scholarship: Faith Keller.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elmer &amp;amp; Bonnie Gilbert Scholarship:  Hannia Garcia.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fegan Family Scholarship:  Selah White and Monique Mays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fegan Family Welding Scholarship: Quinnton Becker and Manuel Sanchez.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Florence McMullen Workforce Development Scholarship: Desneiges Hansen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foundation Student Liaison: Candace Martell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Francis &amp;amp; Jean Smith Scholarship: Megan Lumbrezer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frey Family GED Scholarship:  Christine Kampe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GED Recipient Scholarship: lma Vazquez and Marshayla Thomas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;George Homer and Amy T. Ryan Scholarship: Marshayla Thomas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;George Kreider Memorial Scholarship: Kailey Gash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gov. George H. and Lura Lynn Ryan Scholarship:  Andy Pham.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gerry Sikma Scholarship: Zachary Langlois.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High School Art Exhibit Scholarship: Harley Rudish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hispanic Latino Advisory Committee Scholarship: Hazibeth Morales.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HomeStar Bank &amp;amp; Financial Services Business/Information Technology Endowed Scholarship: Jakob Knox.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HomeStar Bank &amp;amp; Financial Services General Studies Endowed Scholarship: Meara Tilstra.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jace Lillis Memorial Scholarship: Noah Hartsfield.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jack Sarawatz Veterans Scholarship: Zachary Bacon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jerald Hoekstra Family Endowed Scholarship: Rhonda Addison.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jerry Jaffe Memorial Scholarship: Wade Brychta.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Ennen Memorial Scholarship: Makenzie Overacker.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KCC President’s Scholarship: Jayce Hansen and Holly Coulter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kankakee County Home &amp;amp; Community Education Scholarship: Marianna Craighead.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kankakee Kultivators Horticulture Scholarship:  Katie Price.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kankakee River Valley Exchange Club Scholarship: Megan Lumbrezer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kankakee Valley Beverage Association Scholarship: Taylor Roach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KCC Alumni Association Scholarship: Avery Norwick.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KCC Faculty Association Scholarship: Thresia Babiaka.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Larry Forbes Nursing Scholarship: Paul Staneart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Law Enforcement/Paramedic Scholarship: Alannah Anker, Andrew Douglas and James Langer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lawrence “Bud” Schipper Memorial Endowed Scholarship: Kelsey Boudreau.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lester &amp;amp; Virginia Soucie Memorial Scholarship: Skyler Brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lisa Dugan Annual Community Service Scholarship for GED Graduates: Belinda Emery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lucille W. Devine Memorial Endowed Scholarship: Karen Snyder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M. Lois Hayes Memorial Scholarship: Desneiges Hansen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MainSource Bank Scholarship: Joel Orozco-Gaytan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marian Ruth Davenport Nursing: Lachelle Paden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mary M. Tatge Scholarship: Jamisha Jones.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maureen Bushman Endowed Scholarship for Education: Emily Bunting and Danielle Swisher.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maureen Bushman Endowed Scholarship for Nursing: Ethan Stone and Chelsea Henning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mildred Smith Memorial Endowed Scholarship: Katrina Whitten.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milner Broadcasting WVLI/ WIVR/WFAV Scholarship: Mackenzie Delby.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minnetta Fiene Scholarship: Jennifer High.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MLT Scholarship: Dalmary Santiago.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olde Time Farm Show Scholarship: Piaget Felix.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patricia Martin Memorial Scholarship: Clara Capriotti.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patricia M. Paul Memorial Scholarship: Jill Grieff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peg Reeves Scholarship: Hayley Hirano and Lauren Buschek.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PEO Chapter JR Scholarship: Candace Martell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peoples Bank Scholars Scholarship: Tiana Binion, Blair Huffman, Zoey Berwanger, Tiffany Chouinard, Catherine Gray, Aidan Klipp, Mattison Lanie and Courtney Reno.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Psychology Scholarship: Elyse Gustafson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reddish Family Scholarship:  Emily Stewart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ric Edwards &amp;amp; Sonia Baspiniero Edwards Scholarship: Jose Batana.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Gibbs Memorial Scholarship: Riley Spenard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Yohnka Fine Arts Scholarship: Gabrielle Schultz.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rob &amp;amp; Tom Chase Memorial Scholarship: Macenzi Maisonneuve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robert Worth Family Horticulture Endowed Scholarship: Piaget Felix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rochelle &amp;amp; Ivan Meyer Endowed Fund for Cultural Diversity: Alijah Boyd and Phillip Hoover.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rudy &amp;amp; Margaret Minton Memorial Scholarship: Berenice Cintora Villagomez.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sara Lagacy Memorial Nursing Scholarship: Sarah Senesac.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steven L. Smith &amp;amp; Kathryn A. Smith Endowed Entrepreneurship Scholarship: Justin Coggins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tom and Judy O’Brien Family Comes First Endowed Scholarship: Lauran Hickson and Loretta Cousins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VanDrunen Farms Scholarship: Diego Gonzalez.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;William F. Brandenburg Endowed Scholarship: Kyla Brychta.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zeglis Family Endowed Scholarship: Amy Leach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to these students! Have a great semester!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Congratulations to students who earned these awards</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/molly--1.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">LLI sessions September 2018</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/lli-sessions-september-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LLI sessions September 2018" />
      <published>8/22/2018</published>
      <updated>8/22/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/lli-sessions-september-2018</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/lli-sessions-september-2018.html">&lt;p&gt;Canada, stress relief, and online safety are among topics being offered in September as part of the Kankakee Community College Lifelong Learning Institute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lifelong Learning Institute offers affordable, high-quality, non-credit classes that take place in an environment that fosters participation. These classes are open to people ages 50 and older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Canada: Discover the Amazing” is an interactive session that highlights the government, politics, and people that have produced a vibrant culture and a strong economy in our neighbor to the north. The instructor grew up in Toronto and is a former member of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police. Meets Wednesday, Sept. 12 from 1-3:30 p.m. at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Dr. William Bell. Course no.: LLLI 8560; cost is $10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stress-Busting for Family Caregivers of People with Dementia” is designed to improve the quality of life for family caregivers of people with dementia. Topics include managing stress and coping with their situation. Participants receive a handbook, meditation CD, and a relaxation strategies CD. Meets Thursdays, Sept. 13 to Nov. 8 from 2-3:30 p.m. at KCC in Room D124. Facilitator is Cindy DeGroot. Course no.: LLLI 8590.A13. It is a free course, and includes materials. The class is funded by the Northeastern Illinois Area Agency on Aging with funds granted through the Administration for Community Living and Administered by the Illinois Department on Aging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Wonders of Illinois Geology” class offers a visual adventure to experience the diverse natural beauty of Illinois, especially as seen in the state parks. Meets Friday, Sept. 14 from 9:30-11 a.m. at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Max Reams. Course no.: LLLI 9190.A13; cost is $18, includes book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A focus of “Stamp your Passport to Digital Citizenship: Online Safety” will detail tips and tricks to protect your identity and your computer in the digital age. Meets Friday, Sept. 21 from 2:15-3:15 p.m. at KCC in Room D134. Facilitator is Dr. Francesca Catalano. Course no.: LLLI 8610.A13; cost is free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Become a Dementia Friend … What is Dementia Friendly?” is a community awareness presentation to share services and resources embedded in the community. The session supports and educates people with dementia, care partners and families. Meets Friday, Sept. 21 from 102 p.m. at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Cindy DeGroot. Course no.: LLLI 9990.A13. The class is free, and funded through the Illinois Department on Aging from a grant from the Administration for Community Living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel back in time to review great songs in “Origins of Dixieland Jazz.” Dixon will also discuss the impact Louis Armstrong and Billy Kyle made on this music. Meets Tuesday, Sept. 25 from 10-11:30 a.m. at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Willie Dixon, Course no.: LLLI 9620.A13; cost $5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join “Share a Book, share an Author – Non-Fiction” and share a favorite non-fiction author that made an impact on you. Enjoy a discussion on authors and books that helped us learn about our world. Everyone will go home with a list of authors and books. Meets Wednesday, Sept. 26 from 10 a.m. - noon at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Susan Saller. Course no.: LLLI 9820.A13; cost is $7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classes are part of the KCC Lifelong Learning Institute, which offers non-credit, continuing education learning on different intellectual and cultural topics. More information is at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/lli&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/LLI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-30-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kankakee Community College is an accredited two-year college which awards associate degrees and certificates of completion. KCC prepares students both to transfer to four-year colleges and to enter the workforce. The college also offers continuing education courses and certification training, literacy programs, English as a Second Language and GED preparation. The KCC mission is “Enhancing quality of life through learning.” The college has a Riverfront Campus in Kankakee, South Extension Center in Watseka, North Extension Center in Bradley and Manufacturing and Industrial Technology Center in Kankakee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;#&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More KCC news and photos are available at our Newsroom, and on Facebook, Twitter and YouTube. Official college logos are available online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kari Nugent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director of marketing and public relations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;815-802-8256&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;knugent@kcc.edu&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">7 classes offered for people ages 55 and better</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/lli-whitebackground.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Continuing Education classes for September 2018</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/continuing-education-classes-for-september-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Continuing Education classes for September 2018" />
      <published>8/22/2018</published>
      <updated>8/22/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/continuing-education-classes-for-september-2018</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/22/continuing-education-classes-for-september-2018.html">&lt;p class=&quot;center-this-text&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2018-fall-coned-banner-650x365.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Civil War history, Voiceovers and Meditation are among topics being offered in September through Kankakee Community College’s continuing education office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “Why is it called Pickett’s Charge?” Learn why Gen. George Pickett secured a legacy at Gettysburg. Meets Friday, Sept. 7 from 9 a.m. - noon at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Christina Smith. Course no.: LLLI 8470.A13; cost is $19, includes materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gettysburg: From Battlefield to National Park” is about the evolution of the battlefield into a National Park to preserve history. Meets Friday, Sept. 21 from 9 a.m. - noon at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Christina Smith. Course no.: LLLI 8480.A13; cost is $19, includes materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Art and Craft of Writing” is for anyone with a passion for writing. The sessions will include help with writing skills and tools of do’s and don’ts to become a well-rounded writer. Participants are asked to come prepared to write! Meets Thursdays, Sept. 6 to Oct. 25 from 1-2:30 p.m. at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Sue Eggerton. Course no.: LLLI 8430.A13; cost is $65.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In “An Introduction to Voiceovers” explore the fun, rewarding possibilities of the voiceover industry. Participants will learn about different types of voiceovers and the tools to find success. The facilitator will take notes and offer coaching. Meets Wednesday, Sept. 12 from 6-8 p.m. at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Joe Bianco. Course no.: LLLI 8550.Q13; cost is $49.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A Time to Meditate” is for all experience levels. The class includes weekly time to meditate and learn new skills. Meets Monday, Sept. 17 to Oct. 22 from 1:30-2:30 p.m. at KCC in Room D123. Facilitator is Sue Eggerton. Course no.: LLLI 8840.A13; cost is $39.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fresh Fall Design—Fall Topiary” will teach basic floral techniques through hands on instructions to making fabulous topiaries. Participants get to take their completed project home. Meets Monday, Sept. 17 from 6:30-8 p.m. at KCC in Room D151. Facilitator is Kate Batkiewicz. Course no.: LLLI 8400.Q13; cost is $47, includes supplies and completed project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Basic Personal Computer Skills” class teaches how to navigate and customize the desktop, create, find, and save files. It also includes opening, creating, and saving Microsoft Word files, plus much more. Meets Tuesdays, Sept. 18 to Oct. 9 from 2:30-4:30 p.m. at KCC in Room D121. Facilitator is Amber Gocken. Course no.: LLLI 9090.A13; cost is $125, includes textbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the “Basket Weaving” seminar wiith local artisan Sharon Taylor, participants will create their own cute baskets. Everyone gets to keep their creations. Meets Thursday, Sept. 27 form 6-9 p.m. at KCC in Room D151. Facilitator is Sharon Taylor. Course no.: LLLI 9980.Q13; cost is $35, includes supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These courses do not award college credit. To register or for more information, call 815-802-8207; go to www.kcc.edu/comejoinus/; or visit the Welcome Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Seej Nguyen from Pexels.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">A variety of topics are being offered.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/pexel-computer-electronics-laptop-755416.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Online classes for teachers</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/21/online-classes-for-teachers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online classes for teachers" />
      <published>8/21/2018</published>
      <updated>8/21/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/21/online-classes-for-teachers</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/21/online-classes-for-teachers.html">&lt;p class=&quot;center-this-text&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/pexel-tools-teachers-access-book-business-1329068.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Continuing Education Department at Kankakee Community College is offering online classes for teachers. Upcoming start dates are Sept. 12, Oct. 17, Nov. 14 and Dec. 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The courses meet for six weeks and offer 24 professional development contact hours after successful completion. Cost is $94 per course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following are general study areas, along with classes offered in those areas. The classes can be taken individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reading Strategies Suite includes four courses with creative ways to improve student literacy, turn guided reading strategies into opportunities &amp;amp; bring differentiated instruction to the classroom. The classes are: “Ready, Set, Read”; “Guided Reading and Writing: Strategies for Maximum Student Achievement”; “Guided Reading: Strategies for the Differentiated Classroom”; and “Response to Intervention: Reading Strategies that Work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the subject area of “Tools for Teachers,” the course selection includes: “Solving Classroom Discipline Problems,” “Differentiated Instruction in the Classroom,” “Teaching Students with Autism: Strategies for Success,” “Working Successfully with Learning Disabled Students,” “Creating Classroom Centers” and “Survival Kit for New Teachers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Classroom Computing” area includes the following courses: “Integrating Technology in the Classroom,” “Teaching Smarter with SMART Boards” and “Using the Internet in the Classroom.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language courses for teachers include: “Spanish in the Classroom,” “Enhancing Language Development in Childhood” and “Introduction to Teaching  ESL/EFL.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science &amp;amp; math teachers might find these options to be helpful: “Teaching Science: Grades 4-6,” “Introduction to Algebra” and “Teaching Math Grade 4-6.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These courses do not award college credit. More information and registration is at &lt;a href=&quot;www.ed2go.com/kankakeecc&quot;&gt;www.ed2go.com/kankakeecc&lt;/a&gt;. Please phone KCC at 815-802-8207 to make a payment or for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by rawpixel.com from Pexels.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">These continuing education opportunities also offer professional development contact hours.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/pexel-tools-teachers-access-book-business-1329067.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Seminar: Infectious Diseases</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/09/seminar-infectious-diseases.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar: Infectious Diseases" />
      <published>8/9/2018</published>
      <updated>8/9/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/09/seminar-infectious-diseases</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/09/seminar-infectious-diseases.html">&lt;p&gt;The Continuing Education Department at Kankakee Community College is offering a seminar on infectious diseases for health care professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Shampoos, Tattoos &amp;amp; Barbeques” seminar will offer an up-to-the minute update on issues in infectious diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presenter, Barb Bancroft, will share information about new vaccines, diseases and drugs. Bancroft also will review eight new trends, including global warming and travel; bioterrorism; blood-borne illnesses; and infectious agents and their relationship to acute and chronic disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The session meets Thursday, Sept. 20 form 8:30 a.m. - 4 p.m. at KCC in the Auditorium. Course no. is HLTH 394A.A13. Cost is $79, and includes materials and six contact hours for respiratory care technicians, nurses, and nursing home administrators. Contact hours will be awarded following successful attendance at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course does not award college credit. To register or for more information. Call 815-802-8207; go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/comejoinus&lt;/a&gt; (choose KCC Connect and search by course number); or visit the Welcome Center, located on the first floor of the KCC Workforce Development Center.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Health care professionals are invited to this informative session.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/shampoos%20tattoos%20barbeques%20brochure_Page_1.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Online professional development</title>
      
      <link href="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/07/online-professional-development.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Online professional development" />
      <published>8/7/2018</published>
      <updated>8/7/2018</updated>
      <id>http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/07/online-professional-development</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://news.kcc.edu/2018/08/07/online-professional-development.html">&lt;p&gt;The Continuing Education Department at Kankakee Community College is offering online classes for professional development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall start dates are Sept. 12, Oct. 17, Nov. 14 and Dec. 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of classes are offered. They include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Writing Effective Grant Proposals,”&lt;/strong&gt; which includes how to research and prepare grants, including writing a good introduction. The class includes helping the causes you most admire and avoiding errors that lead to rejections. In addition to steps for receiving a grant, there is a discussion of what must be done when the grant arrives. Cost is $115.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Spanish for Medical Professionals”&lt;/strong&gt; is a fun and simple course with tools to bridge the communication gap. This class skip the “touristy” topics and focuses on Spanish usable in a medical setting. Cost is $115. Upon successful completion, 24 contact hours will be awarded to nurses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Spanish in the Classroom”&lt;/strong&gt; is a class that has tossed out long vocabulary lists and complex grammar rules and replaced them with games and stories to make learning easy, painless –  even fun. Lessons include supplemental material to expand your vocabulary. Cost is $115. Upon successful completion, 24 Professional Development hours will be awarded to teachers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;“Certificate in Gerontology”&lt;/strong&gt; is designed to enhance the knowledge and skills of health care professionals who work with the older adults. Cost is $210. Upon successful completion, 25 contact hours will be awarded to nurses, nursing home administrators, social workers, and counselors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;“Certificate in Stress Management,”&lt;/strong&gt; participants examine the relationship between stress and health, nutrition, and physical activity, including how it develops in the workplace. Topics include the psychological and physiological effects of stress, and how stress affects health and well-being. The class will cover effective therapies, including habits such as exercise and diet, which can counteract the negative impact of stress. Cost is $84. Upon successful completion, 14 contact hours will be awarded to nurses, nursing home administrators, social workers, and counselors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Certificate in Women’s Health Issues”&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on issues facing women, both globally and nationally. It addresses physical and mental health issues, with information on specific health issues for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and questioning; effective and empowering communication; and self-care for health and well-being. Cost is $94. Upon successful completion, 14 contact hours will be awarded to nurses, nursing home administrators, social workers, and counselors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Certificate in Perinatal Issues”&lt;/strong&gt; is a multidisciplinary experience to develop skills of individuals who provide care and support for childbearing women, newborns, and families. The course offers a broad understanding of this specialized area of care to stay current with emerging trends. Cost is $115. Upon successful completion, 20 contact hours will be awarded to nurses, social workers and counselors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These courses do not award college credit. More information and additional topics are available online at ed2go.com/kankakeecc or by phoning KCC at 815-802-8207.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      <summary type="html">Professional development classes are offered online.</summary>

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://news.kcc.edu/uploads/inernet-icon.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
