<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>12/20/2018</updated>
  <id>https://news.kcc.edu/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Kankakee Community College</title>
  

  
    <subtitle></subtitle>
  

  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Fall 2018 Honors list</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/19/fall-2018-honors-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fall 2018 Honors list" />
      <published>12/19/2018</published>
      <updated>12/19/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/19/fall-2018-honors-list</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/19/fall-2018-honors-list.html">&lt;p&gt;The following students have been named to the Honors List at Kankakee Community College for the Fall 2018 semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be named to the Honors List, a student must maintain a grade point average between 3.25 and 3.79 and be enrolled in six or more semester hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aroma Park:&lt;/strong&gt; Jasmine Campbell, McKenna Jackson, Vanessa Salazar and Hanna Zarate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashkum:&lt;/strong&gt; Amanda Armold, Brayden Bailey, Matthew Balthazor, Jacob Bramer, Cassidy Gerdes and Andrea Marquez.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beaverville:&lt;/strong&gt; Candace Martell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beecher:&lt;/strong&gt; Joel Barraza and Matthew Villarreal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bellwood:&lt;/strong&gt; Bryan Johnson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonfield:&lt;/strong&gt; Alita Hill, Haley Ireland, Jacob Reilly, Courtney Scott and Megan VanVoorst.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bourbonnais:&lt;/strong&gt; Jeremy Ahlden, McKenna Allen, Kaelyn Anderson, Megan Arseneau, Taylor Beseke, Dustin Blaylock, Alexis Bohlmann, Holly Brown, Brittney Burbridge, Lauren Buschek, Clara Capriotti, Leoneel Cervantes, Anahi Chavez, Steven Doig, Alexis Douglas, Carter Dupuis, Stefanie Flory, Amanda Forman, Joshua Fritz, Haley Garbaciak, Sarid Garcia, Catherine Gray, Victoria Grilli, Rachel Gruhn, Charles Hall, Noah Hartsfield, Kelly Higgins, Emily Hourihan, Blair Huffman, Hailey Johnson, Timothy Keast, Noah Kegg, Jackson Kempen, Danielle Kennedy, Carissa Labriola, Liz Lamilla, Laura Lebda, Brandon Littrell, Andrew Lowry, Riahna McLean, Madeline Memenga, Christopher Nicklas, Avery Norwick, Erika Norwick, Dawn Pacheco, Marissa Patchett, Courtney Paulis, Madison Perkins, Andy Pham, Bryce Porter, Dominic Pusateri, Jessica Ramos Sandoval, Gianna Re, Savannah Reno, Rebecca Rogers, Irene Ruiz, Emma Schriner, Lakeya Smith, Samantha Smothers, Samuel Speiser, Jaime Starkey, Owen Starr, Elizabeth Strand, Aidan Stringer, Carleigh Sunn, Amanda Travis, Jacqueline Valadez, Jessica Varney, Diana Voyt, Aiden White, Joshua Wisniewski, Zachary Woods, Julia Yale and Jakob Zirbel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bradley:&lt;/strong&gt; Michael Bisaillon, Madison Bretveld, Luther Carter, Derek Dandurand, Harley Davis, Madeline Ellexson, Jared Francoeur, Victoria Frye, Dianna Gomez, Savanna Harper, Catherine Henry, Caleb Jackson, Zakary Jackson, Bridget Jamros, Taylor Jones, Dylan Krygsheld, Colin Lamie, Carly Lebeau, Brittany Licka, Megan Mueller, Tyler Myers, Alayna O’Brien, Bradley Stosiek and Kaitlynne Weidner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buckingham:&lt;/strong&gt; Andrew Ireland and Megan Kersten.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cabery:&lt;/strong&gt; Sierra Williams.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Champaign:&lt;/strong&gt; Claire Tang.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charleston:&lt;/strong&gt; Jamie Thompson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chebanse:&lt;/strong&gt; Declan Alexander, Kaitlin Bowers, Megan Dixon, James Ferris, Breanna Heimberger, Heidi Justice, Paris Patrick, Rodney Ponton, Molly Saindon, Brittney Trudeau and Zowie Trudeau.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cissna Park:&lt;/strong&gt; Olivia Powell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clifton:&lt;/strong&gt; Abbey Boudreau, Kyle Buikema, Justin Coggins, Hannah Davis, Alexis Eighnor-Walters, Ethan Fritz, Jeffery Gifford, Morgan Gulick, Taylor Hull, Brian Kirkpatrick, Andrew Riordan and Lauren Zell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cullom:&lt;/strong&gt; Cheyenne Barfield and Jill Grieff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Danforth:&lt;/strong&gt; Jamie Legan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decatur:&lt;/strong&gt; Courtnee Riley.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donovan:&lt;/strong&gt; Tristan Hann.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essex:&lt;/strong&gt; Adam Wright.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frankfort:&lt;/strong&gt; Kayelyn Slager.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gilman:&lt;/strong&gt; Elia Diaz Varela Toni Grayling and Kirsten Schroeder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grant Park:&lt;/strong&gt; Madison Coletti, Andrea Fuentes, Steven Fuentes, Holly Gilliam, Austin Jacobson, Torri Kimbrel and Jill Morse.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Herscher:&lt;/strong&gt; Courtney Key, Kaelyn Mausehund, Jessica Torres and Mary Webber.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joliet:&lt;/strong&gt; Courtney Blan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kankakee:&lt;/strong&gt; Sara Alvarado, Luis Alvarez, Oren Amotz, Joel Azzarelli, Viviana Baeza, Emmanuel Bannerman-Blankson, Nathan Bowers, Cassmine Campbell, Kaycee Carson, Christina Charlier, Brenda Colin-Barron, Michaela Coppotelli, Jessica Drozda, Cruz Duran, Luke Engelman, Stephanie Gardner, Ethan Geisler, Jasmine Gomez, Colleen Grinstead, Joseph Gubbins, Ashley Harwood, Meghann Heck, Courtney Held, Wesley Hemp, Letora James, Heather Jensen, Cody Jones, Ke’Asha Jones, Natalie Jordan, Aliesha Kadlec, Gabrielle Keller, Shane LaReau, Amari Lewis, Kiara Lewis, Mercedes Lopez-Mancilla, Alexandra Lowery, William Lucas, Melissa Luvian, Mitchell Mahnke, Blair Marko, Caley Martin, Ianeli Medina, Christopher Meyer, Brenda Millan, Felicia Miller, Nicholas Mullins, Molly O’Connor, Kalee Odle, Joel Orozco-Gaytan, Jessica Orozco-Zavala, Stefanie Pizano, Erin Reilly, Aurora Rivera, Maria Rivera, Veronica Rossi, Gizelle Salazar-Martinez, Alyssa Schiel, Chloee Schuldt, Nanjala Shaw-McCain, Luis Soto, Andela Spasojevic, Cooper Spiese, Jesse Szczepanski, Michelle Toler, Katelin Trost, Jacquelin Villagomez, Sarah Vinardi, Montell Wilburn, Meloni Williams and Alexander Hoss.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kempton:&lt;/strong&gt; Wyatt Dohe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lockport:&lt;/strong&gt; Shaely Sands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manteno:&lt;/strong&gt; Alexis Andrews, Alyssa Bell, Michael Brady, Regina Cahue, James Deihl, Hayley Easter, Madison Engler, Piaget Felix, Heather Hubbard, Matthew Lynch, Dominique MacLean, Tristain Malone, Damon Myers, Jack Palicki, Rachel Parks, Summer Schimanski, Lyndsie Schleder, Jacob Schreiber, Erin Shackleford Tammy Shields, Jocelyn Stewart, Michael Tomczak and Katelyn Windebank.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martinton:&lt;/strong&gt; Colin Corriveau.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Milford:&lt;/strong&gt; Trenton Hemp and Chelsea Henning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Momence:&lt;/strong&gt; Devin Bales, Hunter Cousin, Cade Harrison, Kassandra Howe, Reily Kane, Michael Layhew, Amy Leach, Jon Lobdell, Connal McBride-Schmars, Cecilia Quirarte, Trevor Reaman, Luisa Rodriguez, Kerri Skiles and Sarah Young.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morris:&lt;/strong&gt;Travis Kohler.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Lenox:&lt;/strong&gt; Jason Hawn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onarga:&lt;/strong&gt; Alondra Barajas, Oscar Camargo and Marisol Melgoza.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Papineau:&lt;/strong&gt; Lauren Chouinard and Mikayla Cole.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pembroke Towship:&lt;/strong&gt; Larkeisha Belmont and Anthony Lopez.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peotone:&lt;/strong&gt; Karah Anker, Eric Osmolski and Colin Sinish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Piper City:&lt;/strong&gt; Crystal Coffey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Royal:&lt;/strong&gt; Jake Schlueter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. Anne:&lt;/strong&gt; Fernando Chagoya, Hannah Lance and Lars Menigoz.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seneca:&lt;/strong&gt; Paige Hacker.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steger:&lt;/strong&gt; Araceli Marez.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stelle:&lt;/strong&gt; Glen Margewich.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sun River Terrace:&lt;/strong&gt; Jammie Shell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tinley Park:&lt;/strong&gt; Jeremy Nelis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watseka:&lt;/strong&gt; Faith Aaron, Stephanie Blackwell, Emily Bunting, Katelyn Davis, Juan Deharo, Blake Deneau, Daniel Devine, Noah Dietchweiler, Cole Giroux, Jordan Godby, Johnathon Gray, Magan Harris, Joseph Jaskula, Larissa Johnson, Justin McTaggart, Amanda Nedza, Katelyn Norder Makenzie Overacker and Ethan Welch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wilmington:&lt;/strong&gt; Nathan Raimondo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bluffton, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; Koltan Moore.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fort Wayne, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; Isabelle Hille.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Huntertown, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; Nolan Lebamoff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newburgh, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; Nathaniel James and Griffin Scaggs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walkerton, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; Michael Machnic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commerce Township, Mich.:&lt;/strong&gt; Aaron Ball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">Congrats to these students!</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/kcc_default_post-placeholder.png" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Fall 2018 President’s list</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/19/fall-2018-presidents-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fall 2018 President's list" />
      <published>12/19/2018</published>
      <updated>12/19/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/19/fall-2018-presidents-list</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/19/fall-2018-presidents-list.html">&lt;p&gt;The following students have been named to the President’s List at Kankakee Community College for the Fall 2018 semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be named to the President’s List, a student must maintain a grade point average of 3.80 or higher and be enrolled in six or more semester hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/hoai-do-of-bourbonnais.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mattison-lanie-of-momence.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;no-float&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mattison-lanie-of-momence.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;no-float&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/hoai-do-of-bourbonnais.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;no-float&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aroma Park:&lt;/strong&gt; DeAndria Wells.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashkum:&lt;/strong&gt; Tricia O’Connor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beaverville:&lt;/strong&gt; Michael Emerson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beecher:&lt;/strong&gt; Dominick Pescetto.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue Island:&lt;/strong&gt; Nathan Morfoot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonfield:&lt;/strong&gt; Hailey Charter, Kimberly Gaddis, Faith Keller, Tara Sandborg, Dominique Schultz and John Wells.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bourbonnais:&lt;/strong&gt; April Balassone, Amanda Barclay, Mallory Bass, Erica Billington, Kaylee Billington, Alexxis Birch, Valerie Brady, Scott Brock, Anthony Buschek, Emma Butterfield, Caleb Campe, Chase Cappellano, Nicholas Clark, Hailee Corkill, Hoai Do, Alexandra Dubravec, Kole El-Talabani, Madalin Evans, Timothy Evett, Tracy Flahaven, John Funk, Matthew Gagnon, Alexandra Garcia, Antonia Guajardo, Kaitlyn Hagge, Elizabeth Hanks, Desneiges Hansen, Emily Hawker, Joseph Jenco, Lisa Jones, Oscar Jones, Rachel Jordan, David Kent, Zachary Langlois, Kephren Lee, McKinley Marcotte, Genevieve Marion, Nicole Martinez, Catelyn Marzke, Lexie McCleary, Johana Morris, Logan Nesselrodt, Emma Ogle, Erik Phelps, Faith Quigley, Matthew Randak, Amanda Roy, Christopher Ryan, Ashley Shepard, John Shivers, Joseph Sikma, Brian Steele, Kailie Thomson, Gabrielle Wagner, Amy Winkle, Brandon Wray and Amanda Zigrossi.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bradley:&lt;/strong&gt; Jessie Baker, Michael Boyer, Olivia Dexter, Steven Elliott, Richard Granger, Elyse Gustafson, Michael Kettley, Brittany LaFond, William McDowell, Jami Meyer, Christina Midvale, Joshua Ollom, Grant Patterson, Nicholas Redmond, Shelby Reeves, Ralph Sansone, Jessica Schilaci, Emily Terrell and Brittany Webb.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Braidwood:&lt;/strong&gt; Steven Tatroe and Dylan Williams.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buckingham:&lt;/strong&gt; Amanda Anderson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cabery:&lt;/strong&gt; Jacob Bruner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Channhon:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin Plumley.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chebanse:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaylee Drummer, Jayce Hansen, Timothy Hoekstra, Adilene Mendoza, Britney Pelletier, Benjamin Schafer, Daniel Snyder, Karen Snyder and Christopher Vaughn.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cissna Park:&lt;/strong&gt; John Nowaczyk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clifton&lt;/strong&gt;: Andrew Boudreau, Erica Cordes, Alyssa Legan, Avery Leveque, Josette Peters, Taylor Roach, Alexander Winkel and David Zell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donovan:&lt;/strong&gt; Trevor Huffman and Jessie Kochenberger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evergreen Park:&lt;/strong&gt; Michael Kealy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gilman:&lt;/strong&gt; Jonathan Davis and Mario Melgoza.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grant Park:&lt;/strong&gt; James Bohl, Richelle Chiattello, Ryan Dandurand, Samantha Greenholt and Nolan Paape.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Herscher:&lt;/strong&gt; Quinnton Becker, Kyla Brychta, Wade Brychta, Alyssa Denault and Kloe Longtin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Irwin:&lt;/strong&gt; Holly Lease.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kankakee:&lt;/strong&gt; Lawrence Agyei, Jose Batana, Brittaney Beck, Tabitha Behnke, Joseph Bilderback, Mary Bilderback, Jana Bonvallet, Xavier Boudreau, Veronica Breach, Alison Buttemeier, Nykearra Calbert, Jeanette Calderon-Munoz, Raeven Carroll, Tiffany Chouinard, Allen Coley, Luke Cross, Peter Dato, Sarah Doris, Jordyn Downing, Deanna Ervin, Jevorne Francis Richards, Felicia Goodrich, Christopher Gottschall, Alison Gryczewski, Amy Hargate, Thomas Harwood, Kyle Haut, Blanca Hernandez-Gonzalez, Kendreea Hodges, Maya Howdeshell, Jorge Juarez-Cuaya, Connor Jumonville, Rachel Kamp, Ronald Mantooth, Ben McCreadie, Allison Mendell, James Morrison, Tali Nordon, Samuel Paisley, Dylan Post, Katharine Raspolich, Jacob Rattin, Alyxandria Rink, Karla Rodriguez-Ramirez, Jorge Santana, Dustin Scheppler, Morgan Scivally, Rita Sproul, Rachel Sumner, Sharon Viers, Kyneca Washington, Jennifer Wei and Erik Young.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kempton:&lt;/strong&gt; Sidney Gunther.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loda:&lt;/strong&gt; Cole Eshleman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manteno:&lt;/strong&gt; Maximilian Aicher, Kathryn Bell, Elan Benge, Kaitlyn Drahos, Maxwell Dumas, Nicholas Fraser, Marissa Hon, Megan Hutchings, Courtney Keller, Madison Koskinas, James Langer, Brent Matherly, LeAnne Mazur, Dave McManus, Kelly Palicki, Joshua Polega, Nickolas Pomykala, Ashley Rock, Lisa Schamber, Christopher Shedwill, Kathleen Sweeney, Brennah Townsend and Ashlee Wesselhoff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martinton:&lt;/strong&gt; Andrea Los.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Milford:&lt;/strong&gt; Richard Younger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mokena:&lt;/strong&gt; Daniel Smith.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Momence:&lt;/strong&gt; David Haut, Taryn Jensen, Carly Johnston, Mattison Lanie, Megan Lanie, Carter Newberry, Roberto Ramirez and Kacie Weishaar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oglesby:&lt;/strong&gt; Cody Schwarting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onarga:&lt;/strong&gt; Tara Heisner and Meara Tilstra.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ottawa:&lt;/strong&gt; Mallory Alderman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pembroke Township:&lt;/strong&gt; Eric Godines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peotone:&lt;/strong&gt; Alannah Anker and Harley Rudish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prophetstown:&lt;/strong&gt; Owen Behrens.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reddick:&lt;/strong&gt; Holly Brown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rockford:&lt;/strong&gt; Alexis Marin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saint Anne:&lt;/strong&gt; Sara Bowman, Lauren Emerson, Christopher Mailhiot, Brian Power and Lydia Salgado.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sheldon:&lt;/strong&gt; Melissa DeMarse, Paula McCarthy and Katherine Morris.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tinley Park:&lt;/strong&gt; Alyssa Gravitt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watseka:&lt;/strong&gt; Jayden Anderson, Eduardo Chavez, Lucas Dart, Samantha Fierstein, Courtney Heath, Shantel Jacobs, Brazliegh Kohl, Kristyn Long, Ben Lyznicki, Hayden Peters, Natalie Schroeder, Cole Taylor, Nathan Wilson and Sadee Wuethrich.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wilmington:&lt;/strong&gt; Dawson Swearengen, Dylan Swearengen and Karolyn White.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grabill, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; Max Minich.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowell, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; David Anderson.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redkey, Ind.:&lt;/strong&gt; Cole Stigleman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos above: Hoai Do of Bourbonnais (left) and Mattison Lanie of Momence (right).&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">Congrats to these students!</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/m-lanie-pres-list-dsc-8164.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Presidential finalists announced</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/17/presidential-finalists-announced.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presidential finalists announced" />
      <published>12/17/2018</published>
      <updated>12/17/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/17/presidential-finalists-announced</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/17/presidential-finalists-announced.html">&lt;p&gt;The Kankakee Community College Board of Trustees has chosen two finalists for the position of college president.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finalists are Dr. Laurie Chesley of Grand Rapids, Mich., and Dr. Michael Boyd of Manteno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community, KCC students and employees are invited to attend open forum sessions with the finalists, at the college from 2-4 p.m. in the college auditorium, Room L110, on the dates of the interviews, Jan. 9 and 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Members of the board are pleased that we had more than 20 applicants,” said Board Chairman Pat Martin. “It was a strong, diverse pool and we look forward to spending time with the two finalists.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/dr--laurie-chesley---small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt;Chesley is the provost and executive vice president for academic and student affairs at Grand Rapids Community College in Michigan. She leads the School of Arts and Sciences, workforce development and student affairs, among other units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chesley teaches in the Doctorate of Community College Leadership Program at Ferris State University, and she also is an AQIP Peer Reviewer with the Higher Learning Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chesley previously served in positions including dean and associate dean of the School of Arts and Sciences at GRCC, dean of Humanities at Montgomery County Community College, assistant vice president for academic affairs at Ferris State University, and interim dean for learning at Northwestern Michigan College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chesley earned her doctorate in English from the University of Notre Dame.&lt;br /&gt;She will be at KCC for an interview on Wednesday, Jan. 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boyd is currently KCC’s vice president for instruction and student success, and chief academic officer. He is responsible for administering credit and non-credit instruction, adult education, and workforce development programs, among other units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/boyd---copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-right&quot; /&gt;Boyd leads initiatives to align academic programs with regional workforce needs, and he also leads KCC’s quality improvement initiatives, which include institutional accreditation and strategic planning.&lt;br /&gt;In addition, Boyd is an Academic Quality Improvement Program (AQIP) Peer Reviewer with the Higher Learning Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, Boyd was associate dean of English, Humanities, and Language Studies at Illinois Central College, where he also served as the college’s Six Sigma Black Belt. He has a doctorate in English Studies from Illinois State University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will be at KCC for an interview on Thursday, Jan. 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KCC board has worked with an advisory committee including representatives from KCC’s faculty, staff, students, the board of trustees and the community. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new president will replace Dr. John Avendano, who has served at KCC since July 2009. Avendano will retire at the end of June. The board plans to make a hiring decision as soon as Jan. 14.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">Open forums set for January 9 and 10</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/presidential-finalists.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">PTK welcomes community outreach founder</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/11/ptk-welcomes-community-outreach-founder.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PTK welcomes community outreach founder" />
      <published>12/11/2018</published>
      <updated>12/11/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/11/ptk-welcomes-community-outreach-founder</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/11/ptk-welcomes-community-outreach-founder.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/sarahdoris-dawnbroers-brittany-lafond.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-right&quot; /&gt;On Thursday, Dec. 6, Phi Theta Kappa’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/students/studentlife/clubs/ptk/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Alpha Delta Eta chapter&lt;/a&gt; Honors in Action co-chairs Sarah Doris and Brittany LaFond presented an informational forum on homelessness in our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guest speaker Dawn Broers, Ph.D., LCSW, executive director and founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortitudecommunityoutreach.org/&quot;&gt;Fortitude Community Outreach&lt;/a&gt;, shared information about her organization and accepted a donation of $330 raised by KCC’s Phi Theta Kappa chapter.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">Donation helps local charity</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/sarahdoris-dawnbroers-brittany-lafond-2.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Alumni profile - Mike Neumann</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/30/alumni-profile-mike-neumann.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alumni profile - Mike Neumann" />
      <published>11/30/2018</published>
      <updated>11/30/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/30/alumni-profile---mike-neumann</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/30/alumni-profile-mike-neumann.html">&lt;p&gt;Mike Neumann’s motto is “Get started and make corrections on the go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t plan to own a business. But today, he is the proud owner of Fit Body U, a thriving gym in Bourbonnais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mikeneumann-kcc-561.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-right&quot; /&gt;Before starting on his own, Neumann worked as a part-time independent contract trainer at a gym. Then, the trainers’ profit margins were cut. “I was backed into a corner,” Neumann says, and he considered a career change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing about a gym for sale, Neumann and a friend collected the money to make the purchase. “It just seemed like perfect timing. But I was flying by the seat of my pants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, Neumann’s new gym was up and running. “I didn’t even have enough equipment for a full gym, but it was enough to get started.” As Fit Body U started making profits, Neumann poured the money back into the business and purchased more equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve learned to appreciate the idea of a small beginnings,” Neumann said. “Some people want to start big and if they’re not sure about what they’re doing, they’ll fall on their face. That’s why I like starting small, and making corrections as I go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neumann helped himself by re-enrolling at Kankakee Community College in his mid-30s. He took two classes at a time and completed a business degree in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re never too old to go back to school,” he said. “You’re never too old to learn. There were so many good classes out here that I took. KCC has everything you need to become a better you and to become a better ‘who you are.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neumann said Microsoft Excel, human resources and communication classes were helpful in providing skills to more effectively run his business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working for 11 businesses, Fit Body U allows Neumann to put his own ideas into practice. “If you work for someone else, you have to work for their vision. But now I can practice my own vision and see how the community responds to my ideas.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last two years, Fit Body U has nearly doubled, from 450 to 810 active members. In the summer of 2019, Neumann is planning a big a big five-year anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’re passionate about a business idea, if that’s what you think about when you’re by yourself, then that’s what you should do,” Neumann says. “People around you will be inspired by your passion and things will come together. If you have consistency and passion, and if you’re always a student of the game, then it will happen.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">&quot;Get started and make corrections on the go.&quot;</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/mike-neumann-d4s-8551.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
