<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>1/2/2019</updated>
  <id>https://news.kcc.edu/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Kankakee Community College</title>
  

  
    <subtitle></subtitle>
  

  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Presidential finalists announced</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/17/presidential-finalists-announced.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presidential finalists announced" />
      <published>12/17/2018</published>
      <updated>12/17/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/17/presidential-finalists-announced</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/12/17/presidential-finalists-announced.html">&lt;p&gt;The Kankakee Community College Board of Trustees has chosen two finalists for the position of college president.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finalists are Dr. Laurie Chesley of Grand Rapids, Mich., and Dr. Michael Boyd of Manteno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community, KCC students and employees are invited to attend open forum sessions with the finalists, at the college from 2-4 p.m. in the college auditorium, Room L110, on the dates of the interviews, Jan. 9 and 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Members of the board are pleased that we had more than 20 applicants,” said Board Chairman Pat Martin. “It was a strong, diverse pool and we look forward to spending time with the two finalists.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/dr--laurie-chesley---small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt;Chesley is the provost and executive vice president for academic and student affairs at Grand Rapids Community College in Michigan. She leads the School of Arts and Sciences, workforce development and student affairs, among other units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chesley teaches in the Doctorate of Community College Leadership Program at Ferris State University, and she also is an AQIP Peer Reviewer with the Higher Learning Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chesley previously served in positions including dean and associate dean of the School of Arts and Sciences at GRCC, dean of Humanities at Montgomery County Community College, assistant vice president for academic affairs at Ferris State University, and interim dean for learning at Northwestern Michigan College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chesley earned her doctorate in English from the University of Notre Dame.&lt;br /&gt;She will be at KCC for an interview on Wednesday, Jan. 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boyd is currently KCC’s vice president for instruction and student success, and chief academic officer. He is responsible for administering credit and non-credit instruction, adult education, and workforce development programs, among other units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/boyd---copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-right&quot; /&gt;Boyd leads initiatives to align academic programs with regional workforce needs, and he also leads KCC’s quality improvement initiatives, which include institutional accreditation and strategic planning.&lt;br /&gt;In addition, Boyd is an Academic Quality Improvement Program (AQIP) Peer Reviewer with the Higher Learning Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, Boyd was associate dean of English, Humanities, and Language Studies at Illinois Central College, where he also served as the college’s Six Sigma Black Belt. He has a doctorate in English Studies from Illinois State University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He will be at KCC for an interview on Thursday, Jan. 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KCC board has worked with an advisory committee including representatives from KCC’s faculty, staff, students, the board of trustees and the community. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new president will replace Dr. John Avendano, who has served at KCC since July 2009. Avendano will retire at the end of June. The board plans to make a hiring decision as soon as Jan. 14.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">Open forums set for January 9 and 10</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/presidential-finalists.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Alumni profile - Mike Neumann</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/30/alumni-profile-mike-neumann.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alumni profile - Mike Neumann" />
      <published>11/30/2018</published>
      <updated>11/30/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/30/alumni-profile---mike-neumann</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/30/alumni-profile-mike-neumann.html">&lt;p&gt;Mike Neumann’s motto is “Get started and make corrections on the go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He didn’t plan to own a business. But today, he is the proud owner of Fit Body U, a thriving gym in Bourbonnais.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mikeneumann-kcc-561.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-right&quot; /&gt;Before starting on his own, Neumann worked as a part-time independent contract trainer at a gym. Then, the trainers’ profit margins were cut. “I was backed into a corner,” Neumann says, and he considered a career change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing about a gym for sale, Neumann and a friend collected the money to make the purchase. “It just seemed like perfect timing. But I was flying by the seat of my pants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, Neumann’s new gym was up and running. “I didn’t even have enough equipment for a full gym, but it was enough to get started.” As Fit Body U started making profits, Neumann poured the money back into the business and purchased more equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve learned to appreciate the idea of a small beginnings,” Neumann said. “Some people want to start big and if they’re not sure about what they’re doing, they’ll fall on their face. That’s why I like starting small, and making corrections as I go.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neumann helped himself by re-enrolling at Kankakee Community College in his mid-30s. He took two classes at a time and completed a business degree in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re never too old to go back to school,” he said. “You’re never too old to learn. There were so many good classes out here that I took. KCC has everything you need to become a better you and to become a better ‘who you are.’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neumann said Microsoft Excel, human resources and communication classes were helpful in providing skills to more effectively run his business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working for 11 businesses, Fit Body U allows Neumann to put his own ideas into practice. “If you work for someone else, you have to work for their vision. But now I can practice my own vision and see how the community responds to my ideas.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last two years, Fit Body U has nearly doubled, from 450 to 810 active members. In the summer of 2019, Neumann is planning a big a big five-year anniversary celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you’re passionate about a business idea, if that’s what you think about when you’re by yourself, then that’s what you should do,” Neumann says. “People around you will be inspired by your passion and things will come together. If you have consistency and passion, and if you’re always a student of the game, then it will happen.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">&quot;Get started and make corrections on the go.&quot;</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/mike-neumann-d4s-8551.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Cash Bash 2019</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/26/cash-bash-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cash Bash 2019" />
      <published>11/26/2018</published>
      <updated>11/26/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/26/cash-bash-2019</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/26/cash-bash-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;Kankakee Community College will sponsor a “Cash Bash” with a $5,000 grand prize from 6:30-11 p.m. Saturday, Feb. 16 at the Quality Inn &amp;amp; Suites, 800 N. Kinzie Ave. in Bradley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be 24 cash prizes, totaling $7,850. To win the $5,000 grand prize or most other cash prizes, the ticket holder does not need to be present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admission is $100 per ticket, and each ticket admits two people for a food buffet and drinks at the event. Only 300 tickets will be sold. Proceeds benefit KCC athletic programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those at the Cash Bash can play Las Vegas-style games. Drawings for at least 20 gift baskets, each valued at $50 or more, also will be held. Gift basket tickets will be sold at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must be 18 years or older to purchase a Cash Bash ticket and 21 years of age or older to attend the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, or to sponsor a gift basket, call KCC’s athletic department at 815-802-8600. A ticket order form can be printed from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/cashbash&quot;&gt;kcc.edu/cashbash&lt;/a&gt; or picked up in the KCC Athletic Department.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">$5,000 grand prize and Las Vegas-style games</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/500x500-cash-bash-graphic.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Register - Spring 2019</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/06/register-spring-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Register - Spring 2019" />
      <published>11/6/2018</published>
      <updated>11/6/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/06/register---spring-2019</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/06/register-spring-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;Kankakee Community College is offering a variety of spring enrollment offerings.&lt;br /&gt;The college lists courses at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/schedule&quot;&gt;www.kcc.edu/schedule&lt;/a&gt; and also has advisement staff to assist new and prospective students with options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/tower-clay-sterling-and-glen--margewich.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt;There are 54 unique subject areas, including classes that meet person, online and as a combination of the two – called hybrid. Some classes have several times to select from, or are offered in more than one location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most classes for the Spring 2019 semester begin the week of Monday, Jan. 7. Early registration is encouraged for the best selection of classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-person registration and advisement is available in Student Services at KCC, which is located on the second floor of the Workforce Development Center. KCC is south of downtown Kankakee, off River Road, near U.S. 45‑52, or take Interstate 57 to Exit 308 and follow the signs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qualified returning students can &lt;a href=&quot;https://selfservice.kcc.edu/Student/Account/Login?ReturnUrl=/Student&quot;&gt;register online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Physical-Science-Ralph-Sansone-and-Paola-Delacruz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-right&quot; /&gt;To make an appointment, or to learn more about the enrollment process, new and returning students can contact the Office of Student Services, 815-802-8500 or visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://register.kcc.edu&quot;&gt;register.kcc.edu&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advisement and registration hours are 8 a.m. - 6 p.m. Monday through Thursday and 8 a.m. - 5 p.m. Fridays. College offices will be closed after 5 p.m. Nov. 21, as well as Nov. 22 and 23. Registration offices will close at noon Dec. 20 and re-open Jan. 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/sec&quot;&gt;KCC Miner South Extension Center&lt;/a&gt;, 1488 E. Walnut St. in Watseka, also offers registration and advisement. The extension center is open Monday through Thursday 8:30 a.m. - 9 p.m., and closed Fridays. Advisement in Watseka is available Tuesdays and Thursdays, and by appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-interesting-kcc-facts&quot;&gt;7 interesting KCC facts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rated No. 1 in Illinois by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zippia.com&quot;&gt;Zippia.com&lt;/a&gt; for helping students land a job after graduation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top 15% of community colleges in the nation for first-time, full-time students who transfer within 2 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The latest pass rates for all health career licensure exams are above the national average, with most at 100%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ranked  No. 2 in North America among associate degree colleges for sustainability practices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average age of Dec. 2017 &amp;amp; May 2018 Associate degree graduates is 26.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practical Nursing program ranked No. 2 in Illinois.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More high school graduates in this area enroll at KCC than any other college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources: KCC Office of Institutional Research, National Community College Benchmark Project (comparison to other participating community colleges); Association for the Advancement of Sustainability in Higher Education; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zippia.com&quot;&gt;zippia.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.practicalnursing.org&quot;&gt;www.practicalnursing.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">Registration for Spring 2019 now available.</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/kcc-student-justin-mctaggert---dsc-7066---copy.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      
      
        <title type="html">Alumni profile - Jacob Jeje</title>
      
      <link href="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/06/alumni-profile-jacob-jeje.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alumni profile - Jacob Jeje" />
      <published>11/6/2018</published>
      <updated>11/6/2018</updated>
      <id>https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/06/alumni-profile---jacob-jeje</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://news.kcc.edu/2018/11/06/alumni-profile-jacob-jeje.html">&lt;p&gt;“It all comes down to passion, drive, and a long-term goal,” says Jacob Jeje.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/jacob-jeje-kcc-13-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;float-image-left&quot; /&gt;Jeje relocated his family from Nigeria to New York for better opportunities. Eventually, they settled in Illinois to be close to relatives. “I was working some crappy jobs, which I did not like,” Jeje said. “I thought about the American dream, that I could decide what I wanted to do, go to college, and get the training I needed to sustain myself and my family.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeje decided to enroll in classes at Kankakee Community College. At first, he tried studying to be a nurse but it didn’t turn out the way he hoped. “I talked with my academic advisor and she encouraged me to focus on the general education courses,” Jeje said. “Not only did her advice help me stay in school but through those courses, I found my career path.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeje switched to KCC’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcc.edu/future/choosing/occupational/manutech/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Manufacturing Technology program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In between a full course load, a full time manufacturing job, and another part time job, Jeje was also a husband and a father. “It was rough, really rough,” he said. “I got about 4.5 hours of sleep every day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeje didn’t always get the perfect grades he wanted because he was balancing many responsibilities. But he wasn’t alone. “My wife has always been super supportive,” Jeje said. “There were days when I wanted to drop some classes and she would say, ‘Just keep going, just keep going.’” He did, as well as earning a spot on the honors list in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He was one of the best Manufacturing Technology students I have ever had,” says Mark Anderson, director of the Manufacturing Technology program, “He had the best grades, the best attendance, the best attitude.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeje completed three certificates from the manufacturing program, plus a KCC associate degree. He also landed a supervisory position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What I studied in school actually helped me get a job really easily,” Jeje said. “Not many people find a job so quickly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeje transferred to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govst.edu/&quot;&gt;Governors State University&lt;/a&gt; in University Park and became the first person in his family to earn a bachelor’s degree. He now works at Pactiv, a manufacturing company. With a short commute, Jeje has more time with his three kids. He’s also taking classes for a master’s degree in supply chain management. “I’m taking it slow this time, and thinking of my long-term goal,” Jeje said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, Jeje says, “If you don’t have a bigger drive beyond just going to school, you’ll be tempted to drop out. Passion keeps you moving, but without a long-term goal, you’ll end up with a degree you can’t get a job with. It’s about balancing all three: passion, drive, and a long-term goals.”&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      

      
      
        <summary type="html">Passion, pride and goals drive this grad</summary>
      

      
      
        
        <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://news.kcc.edu/uploads/jacob-jeje-kcc-137.jpg" />
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
